<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on TMC - 8 Digital Tech</title>
    <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on TMC - 8 Digital Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language><atom:link href="https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/software/</guid>
      <description>To control the LEGO Mindstorms robots running ev3dev, you will need to:
  Open the Company Portal:   Find and install Visual Studio Code (NOT Visual Studio Community):   Install the EV3 MicroPython extension   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the EV3</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/using/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/using/</guid>
      <description>Taken from pybricks.com
Turning the EV3 Brick on and off    Turn on the EV3 Brick by pressing the dark gray center button.
The boot process may take several minutes. While booting, the EV3 Brick status light turns orange and blinks intermittently, and you’ll see a lot of text on the EV3 screen. The EV3 Brick is ready for use when the status light turns green.
To turn the EV3 Brick off, open the shutdown menu with the back button, and then select Power Off using the center button, as shown in Figure 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating and running programs</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/programs/</guid>
      <description>Taken from pybricks.com
 Now that you’ve set up your computer and EV3 Brick, you’re ready to start writing programs.
To make it easier to create and manage your programs, let’s first have a quick look at how MicroPython projects and programs for your EV3 robots are organized.
Programs are organized into project folders, as shown in Figure 8. A project folder is a directory/folder on your computer that contains the main program (main.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structure of program</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/structure/</guid>
      <description>For obscure, historical reasons, the first line must look exactly like this. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, your program won&amp;rsquo;t work at all. Accidentally adding a blank line above or a space before is a common reason your code will break.
1  #!/usr/bin/env pybricks-micropython    The next lines are some explanatory text about what the program in this file does. It is a good habit to do this in Python, but your program will work if you don&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movement</title>
      <link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/robotics/gettingStarted/movement/</guid>
      <description>Set up    # Initialize the motors. left_motor = Motor(Port.B) right_motor = Motor(Port.C) # Initialize the drive base. robot = DriveBase(left_motor, right_motor, wheel_diameter=55.5, axle_track=104) Driving for a given distance or by an angle    Use the following commands to drive a given distance, or turn by a given angle. This is measured using the internal rotation sensors. Because wheels may slip while moving, the travelled distance and angle are only estimates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
