<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Assessment Tasks on TMC - 8 Digital Tech</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/</link><description>Recent content in Assessment Tasks on TMC - 8 Digital Tech</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><atom:link href="https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>R5: Follow the line</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/followTheLine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/followTheLine/</guid><description>In teams (of up to 2), design algorithms using flowcharts to create an automated, driverless vehicle that can stop at line and follow a line. Explore how an automated vehicle might be guided along a road or track and how line detection could be used to save lives. Design ways to improve driving safety by helping to prevent drivers from falling asleep and causing an accident.
Task Description You will need to complete all the following sections as part of your collaborative presentation:</description></item><item><title>R6: Obstacle Course</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/obstacleCourse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/obstacleCourse/</guid><description>In teams of two, you will design algorithms using flowcharts to create an automated, driverless vehicle that can navigate an obstacle course. You will then adapt your code to use a touch sensor and an ultrasonic sensor to complete the same course, and make comparisons between the solutions.
This challenge features a sequence of turns that the robot must perform in order to get to the &amp;ldquo;end&amp;rdquo; of the course. The robot must begin at the starting point and get to the goal area by completing turning and forward movement behaviours.</description></item><item><title>R7: Explorer Project</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/robotExplorer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/robotExplorer/</guid><description>Project Brief Within many fields such as the military, search and rescue, mining and space exploration scientists have been working on autonomous robots they may be used to carry out tasks where it is not safe for people to work. Your team&amp;rsquo;s task is to design and program an autonomous robot that can explore and navigate its way around a room by avoiding walls and other obstacles before running into them.</description></item><item><title>1: Animal Quiz</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/animalQuiz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/animalQuiz/</guid><description>Are you a fan of quizzes? Would you like to make one yourself? In this project, you’ll build an animal quiz. Even though the questions are about animals, this project can be easily modified to be about any other topic.
In this example, you&amp;rsquo;ll see bits of code with annotations. The code in black is new code to be added. The code in grey is existing code; use this to work out where to add the new lines of code.</description></item><item><title>2: My First 2D Game</title><link>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/first2Dgame/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tmcdigitech.github.io/dit8/assessment/first2Dgame/</guid><description>Using the examples worked through in class, you will need to develop the game to have the following features working:
Player movement Collectables Score Collision Events Code with internal comments To Be Successful Include all the above items in your game and complete by the due date. Include comments with all your Python code Use appropriate programming structures (selection and iteration) Purpose Students will be guided through the programming skills and techniques required to complete their final Game Design Project.</description></item></channel></rss>